Everything is suspect... Everyone is for sale... And nothing is what it seems.
L.A. Confidential is a crime, mystery, thriller film directed by Curtis Hanson.
Three detectives in the corrupt and brutal L.A.
police force of the 1950s use differing methods to uncover a conspiracy
behind the shotgun slayings of the patrons at an all-night diner.
Jack Vincennes, played by Kevin Spacey.
Wendell 'Bud' White, played by Russell Crowe.
Edmund 'Ed' Exley, played by Guy Pearce.
Dudley Smith, played by James Cromwell.
Lynn Bracken, played by Kim Basinger.
Sid Hudgens, played by Danny DeVito.
Confidential is a 1997 American neo-noir crime thriller film
directed, produced, and co-written by Curtis Hanson.
The screenplay by Hanson and Brian Helgeland is based on James
Ellroy's 1990 novel, the third book in his L.A.
Quartet series.
The film tells the story of a group of LAPD officers in 1953, and the
intersection of police corruption and Hollywood celebrity.
The title refers to the 1950s scandal magazine
Confidential, portrayed in the film as Hush-Hush.
At the time, actors Guy Pearce and Russell Crowe were
relatively unknown in North America.
One of the film's backers, Peter Dennett, was worried about the lack of established stars in the lead roles, but supported
Hanson's casting decisions, and Hanson had the confidence to also recruit Kevin Spacey, Kim Basinger, and Danny DeVito.
Confidential premiered at the Cannes Film Festival on May
14, 1997, and was released by Warner Bros.
on September 19, 1997.
The film was a critical and commercial success.
It grossed $126.2 million against a $35 million budget and received critical acclaim for the
acting, writing, directing, editing, and Jerry Goldsmith's musical score.
It was nominated for nine Academy Awards, including Best Picture, winning two: Best Supporting Actress
(Basinger) and Best Adapted Screenplay; Titanic won in every other category for which L.A.
Confidential was nominated.
In 2015, the Library of Congress selected L.A.
Confidential for preservation in the United States National Film Registry as
"culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of corruption, based on novel
or book, call girl, shotgun, detective.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.